Illegal wildlife trade in Brazil
الإتجار في الحيوانات في البرازيل
is one of the major threats against our fauna,
هو أحد الأخطار الرئيسية أمام الحيوانات،
especially birds,
خصوصاً الطيور،
and mainly to supply the pet market
وغالباً لتموين سوق الحيوانات الأليفة.
with thousands of animals taken from nature every month,
مع آلالاف الحيوانات تؤخذ من الطبيعة شهرياً،
and transported far from their origins,
ويتم نقلها بعيداً عن موطنها،
to be sold mainly in Rio de Janeiro and São Paulo.
ليتم بيعها في ريدو جانيرو و ساو باولو.
It is estimated that
يتوقع أن
all kinds of illegal wildlife trade in Brazil
كل هذه الأنواع غير الشرعية لتجارة البرية في البرازيل
withdraw from nature
تأخذ من الطبيعة
almost 38 million animals every year,
38 مليون حيوان تقريباً كل سنة،
a business worth almost two billion dollars.
قطاع الأعمال الذي يبلغ تقريباً ملياري دولار.
The police intercepts
تعترض الشرطة
these huge cargos with live animals,
هذه الشحنات الضخمة من الحيوانات الحية،
intended to supply the pet market,
والتي هدفها تزويد سوق الحيوانات الأليفة
or they seize the animals directly from the people's houses,
أو أنهم - الشرطة - يضعون يدهم عليها مباشرة من بيوت المهربين .
and this is how we end up, every month,
وهذا ما ينتهي إليه الأمر، شهرياً،
with thousands of seized animals.
مع آلالاف من الحيوانات المصادرة.
And for us to understand what happens with them,
وبالنسبة لنا لنفهم ماذا يحدث لها،
we're going to follow Brad.
سنقوم بتتبع براد.
In the eyes of many people,
أمام مراقبة الكثيرين،
after the animals are seized,
بعد أن تُصادر الحيوانات،
they say, "Yay, justice has been served.
يقولون، " يااي، لقد حُققت العدالة.
The good guys arrived,
لقد وصل الناس الطيبون،
took the cute, mistreated animals
أخذوا الحيوانات الجميلة التي عوملت بسوء
from the hands of the evil traffickers,
من أيدي المهربين الأشرار،
and everyone lived happily ever after."
وعاش الجميع سعداء بعد ذلك."
But did they? Actually, no,
لكن هل يحصل هذا؟ في الواقع لا.
and this is where many of our problems begin.
وها هنا حيث تبدأ العديد من مشاكلنا.
Because we have to figure out
لأننا يجب أن نعرف
what to do with all these animals.
ما ينبغي علينا فعله بهذه الحيوانات.
In Brazil, they are usually first sent
في البرازيل، في العادة يقومون بإرسالهم بدايةً
to governmental triage facilities,
لمرافق الفرز الحكومية،
in which most of the cases,
التي فيها في معظم الأحيان
the conditions are as bad as
تكون الأحوال سيئة تماماً
with the traffickers.
مثل مع المهربين.
In 2002, these centers received
عام 2002 أستقبلت هذه المراكز
45,000 animals,
45،000 حيوان،
of which 37,000 were birds.
كان بينها 37،000 طائر.
And the police estimates that we seize
وتقدّر الشرطة أننا نصادر
only five percent of what's being trafficked.
خمسة في المائة مما يتم مصادرته.
Some lucky ones -- and among them, Brad --
بعضهم محظوظ، ومن ضمنهم، براد،
go to serious rehabilitation centers after that.
يذهب لمراكز إعادة تأهيل جدية بعد ذلك.
And in these places they are cared for.
وفي هذه الأماكن يتم العناية بهم.
They train their flying,
يمارسون طيرانهم.
they learn how to recognize the food they will find in nature,
ويتعلمون كيفية التعرف على طعامهم، الذي يجدونه في الطبيعة.
and they are able to socialize
ويقدرون على مخالطة
with others from the same species.
كائنات أخرى من نفس الفصائل.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But then what?
لكن ماذا بعد؟
The Brazil Ornithological Society --
جمعية البرازيل للطيور،
so now we're talking only birds --
نحن الآن نتحدث عن الطيور فقط،
claims that we have too little knowledge
هنالك إدعاءات أننا نعرف القليل جداً
about the species in nature.
حول الكائنات في الطبيعة.
Therefore, it would be too risky
وعليه سيكون خطراً
to release these animals,
إطلاق هذه الحيوانات،
both for the released and for the natural populations.
لكلا التي يتم إطلاقها ولبقية الحيوانات.
They also claim that we spend too many resources
ويدعون أيضاً أننا نستهلك الكثير من الموارد
in their rehabilitation.
في إعادة تأهيلها.
Following this argument,
عقب هذه الفرضية،
they suggest that all the birds
يقترحون أن كل الطيور
seized from non-threatened species
المصادرة من الحيوانات غير المهددة
should be euthanized.
ينبغي التخلص منها.
However, this would mean having killed
لكن، هذا يعني أننا سنقتل
26,267 birds,
26،267 طائراً،
only in the state of São Paulo, only in 2006.
فقط في ولاية ساوباولو، فقط عام 2006.
But, some researchers, myself included --
لكن، بعض الباحثين، وضمنهم أنا،
some NGOs and some people from the Brazilian government --
بعض المنظمات الطوعية والمسئولين من الحكومة البرازيلية
believe there is an alternative.
يعتقدون أن هناك بديلاً.
We think that if and when the animals meet
نعتقد أنه إذا كانت هذه الحيوانات وعندما
certain criteria concerning their health,
تستوفي معايير معينة تتعلق بصحتهم
behavior, inferred origin
سلوكها، وتستدل على أصلها،
and whatever we know about the natural populations,
واي شئ نعرفه حول الحيوانات الطبيعية،
then technically responsible releases are possible,
عندئذ يمكن إطلاقهم من الناحية الفنية.
both for the well-being of the individual,
سواء بالنسبة لرفاه الفرد،
and for the conservation of the species and their ecosystems,
وبالنسبة للحفاظ على الكائنات ونظمها الإيكولوجية.
because we will be returning genes for these populations --
لأننا سنقوم بإرجاع جينات هذه الحيوانات
which could be important for them
التي قد تكون مهمة بالنسبة لهم
in facing environmental challenges --
في مواجهة التحديات البيئية.
and also we could be returning
وكذلك قد نرجع
potential seed dispersers, predators, preys, etc.
تفرقاً لبذور محتملة، حيوانات مفترسة، إفتراس، وهلمجرا.
All of these were released by us.
كل هذه تم إطلاقها بواسطتنا.
On the top, the turtles are just enjoying freedom.
في الأعلى ، تتمتع السلاحف بالحرية.
(Laughter)
في الوسط،
On the middle,
هذا الطائر بنى عشاً بعد اسابيع من إطلاقه.
this guy nested a couple of weeks after the release.
في الأسفل، المفضلة لدي شخصياً
And on the bottom, my personal favorite,
الذكر الصغير هناك،
the little male over there,
بعد أربع ساعات من إطلاقه
four hours after his release
لقد كان مع الأنثى من نفس النوع.
he was together with a wild female.
إذاً، هذا ليس جديداً، كان الناس
So, this is not new, people have been
يفعلون هذا حول العالم.
doing this around the world.
لكنه ما يزال موضوعاً كبيراً في البرازيل.
But it's still a big issue in Brazil.
نحن نعتقد أننا قمنا
We believe we have performed
بإطلاق بكل مسئولية.
responsible releases.
لقد قمنا بتسجيل تزاوج للحيوانات المُطلق سراحها في الطبيعة،
We've registered released animals mating in nature
وحصولهم على فراخ.
and having chicks.
لذا، هذه الجينات بالتأكيد ترجع لمواطنها.
So, these genes are indeed going back to the populations.
لكن ما تزال هناك قلة
However this is still a minority
بسبب قلة المعرفة.
for the very lack of knowledge.
لذا، أقول لندرسهم أكثر، لنسلط الضوء على هذه القضية،
So, I say, "Let's study more, let's shed light on this issue,
لنفعل كل ما بوسعنا.
let's do whatever we can."
أنا أكرّس كل عملي لذلك.
I'm devoting my career to that.
وأنا هنا لأحثّ كل شخص منكم
And I'm here to urge each and every one of you
ليفعل كل مافي مقدوره،
to do whatever is in your reach:
ليتحدث لجاره، يعلم أطفاله،
Talk to your neighbor, teach your children,
تأكد من أن حيوانك الأليف من مربى قانوني.
make sure your pet is from a legal breeder.
نحتاج للعمل، والعمل الآن
We need to act, and act now,
قبل أن تكون هذه هي آخر المتبقية.
before these ones are the only ones left.
شكراً جزيلاً لكم.
Thank you very much.
(تصفيق)